the question mark it's one of the most powerful characters in the javascript
问号 它是 javascript 世界中最强大的字符之一
universe providing syntactic sugar in three awesome yet totally unrelated ways
以三种令人敬畏但完全不相关的方式提供语法糖
first up we have the ternary operator the word ternary literally means
首先我们有三元运算符三元这个词的字面意思是
composed of three parts using the question mark as our starting
由三个部分组成使用问号作为
place we add a condition on the left side then on the right side
我们添加的起点 左边的条件然后右边的
we add a value to a sign when the condition is truthy but if the
我们在条件为真时为符号添加一个值，但如果
condition is falsy we add a colon to assign a different value the operator is
条件为假，我们添加一个冒号来分配不同的值，该运算符
often used to replace a traditional if statement the code in a ternary
通常用于替换传统的if 语句 三元
expression is far more concise but you might argue that it's much less
表达式中的代码要简洁得多，但是您可能会争辩说它
readable than an if statement and you might be right that is until you
比 if 语句的可读性要低得多，而且您可能是对的，直到您
need to assign a variable a statement like if is code that does
需要为变量分配一个语句，例如 if 是执行
something it's imperative it begins with state then as the
某些命令的代码，它以 state 然后随着
program's executed it mutates the state and takes multiple lines of code just to
程序的执行，它会改变状态并使用多行代码来
assign a variable based on a simple condition
根据一个简单的条件分配一个
the ternary operator on the other hand creates an expression which means that
变量 另一方面， y 运算符创建一个表达式，这意味着
it produces a value that we can then assign to a variable
它产生一个值，然后我们可以将其分配给一个变量。
this code is declarative it describes the state of the variable
这段代码是声明性的，它描述了变量的状态，
as opposed to mutating it that's why we can use const here but require
而不是改变它，这就是为什么我们可以在这里使用 const 但需要
let in the if statement declarative code is awesome because it can also be used
let 在 if 语句中，声明性代码很棒，因为它也可以
in function arguments and in array and object literals but the question mark
用于函数参数以及数组和对象字面量中，但是问号
isn't done there in 2020 an awesome new feature landed in
在 2020 年还没有完成
javascript called optional chaining at some point you've likely written code
可能编写的
that calls an object property that does not exist and when that happens it
代码调用了一个不存在的对象属性，当这种情况发生时它
triggers an error at runtime you could write some code
会在运行时触发一个错误，您可以编写一些代码
that asserts a property exists before calling it
在调用它之前断言一个属性存在，
but this can get really ugly nowadays you can just insert a question mark
但是现在这可能会变得非常丑陋，您可以
between the property name and the period between the next property
在它们之间插入一个问号 如果父属性未定义，则属性名称和下一个属性之间的句
if the parent property is undefined it'll just return undefined instead of
点将只返回未定义而不是
throwing an error that's a truly life-changing feature for
引发错误 对于 javascript 开发人员来说，这是一项真正改变生活的功能，
the javascript developer but the question mark has one more trick
但问号还有一个
up its sleeve nolish coalescing in many cases you may want to set a
技巧 nolish 合并在许多情况下，您可能希望
default value for a missing variable or property name
为缺少的变量或属性名称设置默认值，
you can easily do that with a logical or operator if the left side is falsy
您可以轻松地使用逻辑或运算符如果左侧是假的，
then use the value on the right side but because javascript has a bunch of weird
则使用右侧的值，但是因为 javascript 有一堆奇怪的
rules for what is truthy and falsey you may get weird results like an empty
规则来判断什么是真假，你可能会得到奇怪的结果，比如空
string or zero being set to a default value because it resolves to falsey
字符串或零被设置为默认值，因为它解决了 虚假
instead of logical or you can add a double question mark which works just
而不是逻辑，或者您可以添加一个双问号，其工作方式
like logical or except undefined and null are the only
与逻辑或除了 undefined 和 null 是
values that short circuit to the right side making the behavior of your code
唯一短路到右侧的值，使您的代码的行为
much more predictable this has been the javascript question
更加可预测这一直是 javascript
mark in 100 seconds if you want to see more short videos
问号 在 100 秒内如果您想看更多这样的短视频，请
like this make sure to hit the like button and subscribe
确保点击“赞”按钮并订阅
thanks for watching and i will see you in the next one
感谢观看，我会在下一个看到你